Vincent Wong

vinymwong@gmail.com ❖(+44) 7729264873 ❖Bristol, UK ❖wongyikming.com ❖LinkedIn ❖GitHub

Due to graduate in 2021. Competent in multiple programming languages, algorithms, as well as teamwork and business skills gained from experiences such as internship and team programming challenges. Specialized in software engineering and pursuing further studies into cybersecurity and artificial intelligence.

WORK EXPERIENCE AND PROJECTS

Moovup. – Developer Summer Intern

Jul. 2019 – Sep. 2018

- Collaborated closely with developers and PM to deliver software quality assurance in an agile environment
- Ensured backwards compatibility for new features through introducing automated integration tests
- Implemented backend features such as an endpoint for job search, using: Clojure, SQL, GraphQL, Elasticsearch
- Learnt how to develop production ready code, and understand the development flow within a startup company

MATLAB minidrone competition

Aug. 2019 – Oct. 2018

- Designed a line follower algorithm using model-based design within Simulink, and achieved 3rd runner up
- Deployed the algorithm on hardware and eliminated errors from real-world conditions under time pressure

University of Bristol Student Laptop and Mobile Clinic – Technician

Sep. 2019 – Present

- Provide technical support to students, meanwhile developing my interpersonal and technical skills
- Demonstrated my ability to deliver customer services

AI for board game "Scotland Yard"

Feb. 2019 – May. 2019

- Achieved 2nd runner up for the performance of the AI against humans
- Shared expertise with teammates by developing the AI collaboratively using Git and effective communication
- Implemented Dijkstra's shortest path finding algorithm for AI scoring method; Design patterns are also utilized

local jewelry shop – Web developer

Aug. 2018 - Sep. 2018

Successfully promoted online appearance through optimizing SEO and targeted audience with analytical tools

La Salle College IT Club - Chairman

Aug. 2015 - Sep. 2016

Bring together committee members, and successfully organized a series of CS workshops for fellow students

OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS

Gold certificate – UK Senior Mathematical Challenge Bronze award – The Hong Kong Olympiad in Informatics Champion – mobile app design competition

November 2016

2014/15

2015

EDUCATION

BSc Computer Science – University of Bristol

Sep. 2018 - Present

First Class Honours

Units: Computer Architecture; Language Engineering; Data Structures and Algorithms; Probability and Statistics; Communication, complexity and number theory; Concurrent Computing; Imperative, Functional and Object-Oriented Programming; Databases and Cloud Concepts

Active engagement with the Computer Science Society, participated in team programming challenges such as Google Hashcode and BAE cybersecurity Capture the Flag; Orienteering society; Hong Kong public affairs and social service soc.

A-levels – King Edward VI College, Stourbridge

Sep. 2016 – Jul. 2018

- A* and 4As, including A* in Math, and A in Computer Science, Further Math, Economics and Chinese
- Subject award in Computer Science, designed a scheduling algorithm for my independent project

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Technical skills

- Web development, JavaScript MVC, Vue.js; Relational DB, SQL; Cybersecurity
- Object-oriented programming: Python, Java, Django; Imperative: C, C++; and functional: Haskell
- Data Analysis; Microsoft Office, Excel, Word, PowerPoint;

Other skills

Teamwork; Research; Customer Service; Management; Public Speaking; Leadership

Interests

economics; diversity; orienteering sports; photography; volunteering